# Maksim Varenkov

# Senior Software QA Engineer

## Maksim "Max" Varenkov

Cedar Park, TX 78613

857.990.8284 maxim.varenkov@gmail.com

# **Summary**

Expert in QA processes and SDLC. Delivery of quality software, products, systems, and applications to meet business, market, and customer needs.

11+ years QA experience testing front-end and back-end software applications.

Develops and maintains automation testing frameworks using Java, JUnit, Cucumber, Selenium, and RestAssured.

Sets up tests in continuous deployment pipelines for UI, API, and various back-end applications using Jenkins.

Implements dockerized test execution.

Writes detailed test cases, test plans, and documents identified defects.

Excellent interpersonal and communication skills; a self-starter, team player, with the ability to work under pressure during tight deadlines with excellent analytical and problem-solving skills.

# **Experience**

#### Elligo Health Research / QA Engineer

JANUARY 2021 - APRIL 2024, Bee Cave, TX

Manual (60%) and automated testing Selenoid\Selenium WebDriver + Java + Serenity (40%) of company products.

Maintained and improved the testing environment, test documentation management, and data verification for audit and FDA reports.

Implemented new test scenarios, code review, and hosted educational sessions for colleagues.

Worked with two teams of engineers to ensure the highest quality of company products.

Acted as the last support line as applicable.

#### Wayfair / QA Engineer II

APRIL 2019 - JULY 2020, Boston, MA

Manual (20%) and automated testing Selenide\Selenium WebDriver + Java + Cucumber + Maven (80%) of company products.

Maintained and improved the testing environment and documentation.

Implemented new test scenarios and improved existing framework with additional features; took code ownership and code review; and hosted educational sessions for colleagues.

#### Semrush CZ/ QA Engineer

MAY 2017 - JANUARY 2019, Prague, Czech Republic

Performed manual and automated testing (Selenide\Selenium WebDriver + Java + TestNG + Maven) of company products.

Maintained and improved the current testing environment and managed test documentation.

Created a complete architecture of automated testing for a project including UI testing prototype.

# Wisebits / QA Engineer

MAY 2015 - MAY 2017, Limassol, Cyprus

Performed manual and automated testing of new features (WebDriver + PHPUnit) for high-loaded web-application.

Maintained the current automation testing system while creating new tests for features.

## Lavtech / QA Engineer

JANUARY 2013 - MAY 2015, Moscow, Russian Federation

Performed functional and automated testing (Selenium WebDriver + JUnit) and completed test documentation management.

Initialized a QA lifecycle for the project from scratch.

#### **Technical Skills**

Automation: JUnit, Cucumber, TestNG, Selenium, Selenide, Selenoid,

Maven, Jenkins, Docker, CI\CD, GitLab, GitHub

Web/Programming: Java, HTML, CSS, SQL, XML

Databases: MsSQL

Testing tools: RestAssured, Postman, Jira, Zephyr

#### **Education**

#### Smolensk Industrial and Economic College / Associate

SEPTEMBER 2006 - JUNE 2010, Smolensk, Russian Federation

Computer science.